Dell H. Hymes Papers 1947-1992 Mss.Ms.Coll.55
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1951-1987; 17 lin. feet (Box 1-32)
  - Whitehall, Harold, 1955
  - Whiteley, W. H., 1968
  - Whiteman, Marcia, 1979-1980
  - Whitman, Randel, 1965
  - Wienckowski, Louis A., 1979
  - Wiget, Andrew, 1982-1984
  - Willard, William, 1981
  - William T. Grant Foundation, 1979,1983
  - Williamson, Craig & Susan, 1971-1975
  - Willie, C. Sylvia W., 1963
  - Willis Jr., William S., 1970-1976
  - Wilmsen, Edwin, 1977-1984
  - Wilson, Eileen H., 1977
  - Winkin, Yves, 1978-1985
  - Winter, Werner, 1965
  - Wisbey, Roy, 1962-1963
  - Witkowski, Stanley & Brown, Cecil, 1981,1984
  - Wolcott, Harry, 1968
  - Wolf, Eric, 1961-1972,1975
  - Wolfe, Susan J., 1984
  - Wolfers, Edward P., 1969
  - Wolff, Kurt H., 1969-1973,1978
  - Wolfowitz, Clare, 1982-1983
  - Wolfson, Nessa, 1979,1985
  - Wood, Richard E., 1978,1984
  - Woods, John, 1969
  - Worsely, Peter, 1970-1971
  - Worth, Sol, 1966-1977
  - Wurm, S. A., 1968-1969
  - Yaeger, Malcah, 1969-1974
  - Yale University Press, 1970
  - Yengoyan, Aram, 1978-1979
  - Yerkovich, Sally, 1974-1980
  - Yoder, Don, 1971
  - Young, Jane, 1980
  - Zaretsky, Kathleen, 1971
  - Zatta, Jane Dick, 1983
  - Zenk, Henry B., 1981
  - Zentella, Ana Celia, 1981-1982,1986
  - Zgusta, L., 1963-1968
  - Zolbrod, Paul G., 1977-1983
  - Zwicky, Arnold, 1977-1978,1981
  - Subseries A. Letters of Recommendation, 1 lin. feet
    These have a 25-year restriction (2029) and are arranged alphabetically.
    - A-L (Box 33)
    - M-Z (Box 34)
- Series II. Conferences and Committees, 1955-1987; 11 lin. feet
  This series contains Hymes' extensive work with professional organizations, government agencies, and committees including minutes, reports and correspondence.
  As in Dr. Hymes' correspondence many of the letters have carbon-copied responses on the reverse of the originals or on scrap paper. Arranged alphabetical by organization.
  Note: see also names mentioned in corresponding Series I.
  - Subseries A. American Anthropological Association (Box 35-39)
    Contains considerable coverage of the ethics committee work with the issue of anthropologists in Thailand in the early 1970s and the Simon Fraser University controversial firing of professors in their political science, sociology and anthropology department. Hymes was president-elect and president from 1981-1982. Much of this material is on the association's reorganization. Many individual committee reports are contained within the annual reports.
    - Ad Hoc Committee to Evaluate the Controversy Concerning Anthropological Activities in Relation to Thailand, 1971
    - Advisory Panel on Guatemala, 1982-1983
    - American Anthropologist, 1962-1971,1979
    - American Ethnological Society, 1965-1966,1981-1982
    - Annual Report, 1981-1983
      - Memos Number 5,13,18,43-89, 1981
      - Memos Number 2-20, 1982
      - Memos Number 21-60, 1982
      - Memos Number 61-85, 1982
      - Memos Number 86-114, 1982
      - Memos Number 1-30, 1983
      - Memos Number 31-60, 1983
      - Memos Number 61-87, 1983
    - Anthropology Newsletter, 1978,1981-1983
    - Committee on Anthropological Research in Museums (CARM), 1970
    - Committees on Reorganization, 1968-1983
    - Congressional Research Service Draft Report for Committee on Science & Technology, U.S. House of Representatives, 1985
    - Cooperating Societies, 1982-1983
    - Correspondence, 1962-1969,1972-1987; 5 folders
      - Folder 1, 1962-1969,1972-1979
      - Folder 2, 1980-1982
      - Folder 3, Jan.-May 1983
      - Folder 4, June-Dec.1983
      - Folder 5, 1984-1987
    - Correspondence regarding Reorganization, 1982-1983; 2 folders
      - Folder 1, 1982
      - Folder 2, 1983
    - Council on Anthropology and Education
      - Anthropology and Education Quarterly, 1976-1979
      - Committee Reports, 1978-1983
      - Executive Committee, 1976-1980; 2 folders
        - Folder 1, 1976-1978
        - Folder 2, 1979-1980
      - Nominations Committee, 1978-1979
      - Program in Anthropology and Education, 1967-1969
    - Crawford vs. Lundsgaarde, et al, 1981,1983
    - Distinguished Lecturer, 1981-1987
    - Distinguished Service Award, 1978-1983,1987
    - Ethical Issues, 1985
    - Ethics Committee
      - Ethics Committee, 1969-1970,1980-1983
      - Liaison to the Executive Board, 1970-1971
        - Folder 1, July-Aug. 1970
        - Folder 2, Sept. 1970-1971
      - Simon Fraser University - Political Science, Sociology and Anthropology Department, 1969-1971; 2 folders
        - Folder 1, 1969-July 1970
        - Folder 2, Aug. 1970-1971
      - Thailand Controversy, March-June 1970; 3 folders
        - Folder 1, March 1970
        - Folder 2, April 1970
        - Folder 3, May-June 1970
    - Executive Board, 1966-1971, 1981-1983; 2 folders
      - Folder 1, 1966-1971
      - Folder 2, 1981-1983
    - Executive Board Motions to be executed by the President, 1982-1983
    - General Section Organization, 1983
    - Motion on Association Review and Comment on Federal Historic Preservation Regulations, Guidelines, and Related Documents, 1982-1983
    - Motion on the Situation of the Indians in Brazil, 1983
    - Motion on Termination of the US Trusteeship in the Islands of Micronesia, 1982-1983
    - Pamphlet on Careers. "Moving out Beyond the Academy", 1981
    - Plans for the Edward Sapir Centennial,1984, 1982-1983
    - Platform by J. V. Murra, n.d.
    - Resolutions, 1981
    - Society for Linguistic Anthropology, 1981-1983
    - Society for the Anthropology of Visual Communication, 1973-1974,1977,1979-1980,1986
  - Subseries B. Conferences on Pidginization and Creolization of Languages (Box 40-41)
    Papers from two conferences-- one at the University of the West Indies, Mona, Jamaica (April, 1968) and the other at the College of the Virgin Islands in St. Thomas (March, 1979).
    - Conference at the College of the Virgin Islands, St. Thomas, 1978-1980
      - Correspondence, 1978-1980
      - Notes, [1979]
      - Notes, Editorial, [1979-1980]
      - Papers, [March 1979]; 3 folders
    - Conference at the University of the West Indies, Mona, Jamaica, 1963, 1966-1972, n.d.
      - Correspondence, 1963, 1966-1972, n.d.; 3 folders
        - Folder 1, 1963,1966-1967
        - Folder 2, 1968
        - Folder 3, 1969-1972, n.d.
      - Notes, [1966-1968]
      - Papers, [April 1968]; 2 folders
      - Proceedings, 1968
    - List of Verbs, n.d.
    - Symposium on the Relationship between Pidginization, Creolization and Language Acquisition - Correspondence, 1979-1980
    - Swadesh's 200 items list in 3 Creole languages of Surinam, n.d.
    - Third Biennial Conference of Society for Caribbean Linguistics - "The Social History of Dread Talk", n.d.
  - Subseries C. Linguistic Society of America (Box 41-44)
    Materials of the society while Hymes was president in 1982. Of particular interest is his work with the joint AAA-LSA committee on the Edward Sapir centennial.
    - Ad Hoc Committee to Study Natural Language Research, 1985
    - Ad Hoc Joint AAA-LSA Committee on the Edward Sapir Centennial, 1983-1984; 2 folders
      - Folder 1, 1983
      - Folder 2, 1984
    - Ad Hoc Search Committee, 1982,1986-1987
    - Advisory Committee on the Fund for the Future of Linguistics, 1982-1983,1986
    - Agreements with the Center for Applied Linguistics, 1980-1983
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1981-1982,1985-1986
    - American Council of Learned Societies, 1981-1982
    - Board of Editors - Collected Works of Edward Sapir, 1983-1984; 2 folders
      - Folder 1, 1983-July 1984
      - Folder 2, Aug.-Sept. 1984
    - Bylaws of the Joint National Committee for Languages, 1981-1982
    - Comite International Permanent des Linguistes (CIPL), 1981-1983
    - Committee of Presidents, 1981-1982,1986
    - Committee on Archives, 1980-1983,1985-1986
    - Committee on Careers for Linguists, 1980-1983,1985-1986
    - Committee on Committee and Delegate Appointments, 1981-1983
    - Committee on Honorary Members, 1980,1982-83,1985-86
    - Committee on Information and Documentation Services, 1971-1972
    - Committee on Linguistic Institutes and Fellowships, 1980-1986; 2 folders
      - Folder 1, 1980-1982
      - Folder 2, 1983-1986
    - Committee on Linguistics and the Public Interest, 1973,1977
    - Committee on Membership, 1969-1970
    - Committee on the Status of Women in Linguistics, 1980-1986
    - Committee on Travel Grants, 1981-1983
    - Consortium of Social Science Associations (COSSA), 1981-1983,1985-1986
    - Correspondence, 1971, 1973-1976, 1980-1987
      - Folder 1, 1971,1973-1976
      - Folder 2, 1980-1982
      - Folder 3, 1983-1987
    - Exchange of Advertisements, 1982
    - Federation of Behavioral, Psychological, and Cognitive Sciences, 1981
    - Finance Committee, 1981-1983
    - Ford Foundation, 1982
    - Language Review Committee, 1980-1986; 2 folders
      - Folder 1, 1980-1982
      - Folder 2, 1983-1986
    - Letter from Charles Hockett to Victoria Fromkin with responses, 1982-1983
    - Linguistics in the Undergraduate Curriculum, 1985-1986
    - Linguistics Panel, 1981
    - National Endowment of the Humanities Challenge Grant Proposal, 1982-1983,1986
    - Nominating Committee, 1981-1987
    - Officers and Executive Committee, 1966,1968-1970, 1980-1987; 3 folders
      - Folder 1, 1966,1968-1970
      - Folder 2, 1980-1982
      - Folder 3, 1983-1987
    - Postal rates, 1982
    - Program Committee, 1980-1986
    - Social Science Research Council, 1981-1985
    - Symposium: Sexism, Semantics and Discourse, 1984
      see also Committee on the Status of Women in Linguistics
  - Subseries D. Social Science Research Council (Box 45-48)
    Largely Hymes' work with the committee on sociolinguistics from its inception to its demise (1963-1980).
    - Applications of Linguistics, 1974
    - Applied Sociolinguistics: an Arena for the Committee on Sociolinguistics?, 1975
    - Chicano Tejano Mexicano by Los Atrevidos, 1972
    - Committee on Nominations, 1978-1980
    - Committee on Problems and Policy, 1964,1972
    - Committee on Sociolinguistics, 1961, 1963-1980; 25 folders
      - Folder 1, 1961, 1963-1965
      - Folder 2, Jan.-June1966
      - Folder 3, July-Dec.1966
      - Folder 4, 1967
      - Folder 5, 1968
      - Folder 6, 1969
      - Folder 7, 1970
      - Folder 8, 1971
      - Folder 9, Jan.-June 1972
      - Folder 10, July-Dec.1972
      - Folder 11, Jan.-April 1973
      - Folder 12, May-Dec.1973
      - Folder 13, Jan.-June 1974
      - Folder 14, July-Dec.1974
      - Folder 15, Jan.-April 1975
      - Folder 16, May 1975
      - Folder 17, June-Sept.1975
      - Folder 18, Oct.-Dec. 1975
      - Folder 19, Jan.-June 1976
      - Folder 20, July-Sept. 1976
      - Folder 21, Oct.-Dec.,1976
      - Folder 22, Jan.-Feb.1977
      - Folder 23, March-Aug.,1977
      - Folder 24, Sept.-Dec. 1977
      - Folder 25, 1978-1980
    - Conference on Comparative Ethnographic Analysis of Patterns of Speech in the United States, 1972-1975
    - Conference on the Ethnography of Speaking, 1972
    - Executive Committee, 1964-1975, 1980; 3 folders
      - Folder 1, 1964-1969
      - Folder 2, 1970-1971
      - Folder 3, 1972-1975, 1980
    - Georgetown University Round Tables, 1970-1982
    - Language and other Learning after Childhood, [1975]
    - Language Research Foundation, 1971
    - Linguistic Research in Great Britain in Relation to the Social Sciences, 1973
    - Mailing List of the Group for the Study of Sociolinguistics (GSSL), 1967
    - Multiple Analysis Project, 1976,1982
    - Proposed Conferences, Study Groups, Workshops, Summer Institutes, 1975-1978, n.d.
    - Research Training Fellowships, 1956,1958,1962,1964
    - State of the Field of Sociolinguistics, Progress Report, and Future Projects, 1973
    - Sub-Committee on Acquisition of Communicative Competence, 1965-1967
    - Toward a Sociology of Language, 1971
    - Twenty-third Annual Georgetown University Round Table, 1970-1972; 2 folders
      - Folder 1, 1970-1971
      - Folder 2, 1972
  - Subseries E. Other Committees (Box 48-56)
    Some include the Academy of Arts and Sciences, the American Association of Applied Linguistics, the American Folklore Society, the Center for Applied Linguistics and other University of Pennsylvania committees.
    - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, 1981
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences
      - Council, 1974,1979-1982
      - Fellow, 1974,1980
      - National Humanities Center Conference, 1974
      - Social Science Prize Committee, 1971-1980
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1982-1986
    - American Association for the Advancement of the Humanities, 1981-1982
    - American Association of Applied Linguistics, 1977-1980, 1984-1987; 6 folders
      - Abstracts and Evaluations for Papers presented at Meetings, 1984-1985
      - Correspondence, 1977-1980,1984-1987
      - Nominating Committee, 1983-1986
      - Officers and Executive Committee, 1984-1987; 2 folders
        - Folder 1, 1984-1985
        - Folder 2, 1986-1987
      - Program Committee, 1984-1986
    - American Folklore Society, 1973-1978; 2 folders
      - Folder 1, 1973-1976
      - Folder 2, 1977-1978
    - American Institute for Marxist Studies, 1965-1967
    - American Society of International Law - Communications and Linguistics Study Group, 1967
    - American Sociological Association - Sociology Liberation Movement, 1969
    - Amsterdam Festival of Social Sciences, 1974-1975
    - Anthropologists for Radical Political Action, 1970-1972
    - Arizona State University - Program of Religious Studies - Religious Character of Native American Humanities, 1977
    - Association for a World Language/Council on International Communication, 1963-1978
    - Association of American Indian Linguists, 1980
    - Association of Teachers of Japanese, 1980-1981
    - Behavioral and Social Sciences Survey Committee - Anthropology Panel, 1967-1970
    - Berkeley Linguistics Society, 1984-1985
    - Canada Council, 1977-1978
    - Center for Advanced Study in Behavioral Sciences, 1958-1979,1985
    - Center for Applied Linguistics - Board of Trustees, 1972-1981, 1983; 4 folders
      - Folder 1, 1972-1974
      - Folder 2, 1975-1976
      - Folder 3, 1977
      - Folder 4, 1978-1981,1983
    - Centre for Advanced Study in the Developmental Sciences, 1968-1970
    - Centre International de Semiotique et de Linguistique d'Urbino, 1967,1971-1978
    - Cherion: The International Society for the History of Behavioral and Social Sciences, 1971-1974
    - City College of New York - Anthropology Department, 1971-1972
    - Classification Society, 1964-1970
    - Colorado College - Centennial Symposium, 1974-1975
    - Columbia University - Lionel Trilling Seminars, 1982
    - Conference on Ethnography and Writing Fiction, 1971-1972
    - Conference on Language, Children and Society, 1975-1978
    - Consortium of Social Science Associations - Board of Directors, 1982-1984
    - Council on International Communications - Board of Directors, 1977-1981
    - Cross Cultural Resource Center - Seminar on Bilingualism and Bilingual Education Beyond Compliance, 1981
    - Delius Society, 1972,1977,1980
    - Edward Sapir Centenary Conference, Ottawa, October,1984, 1982-1985
    - Frank L. Weil Institute of Advanced Studies in Religion and the Humanities, 1960-1967
    - Georgetown University - School of Languages and Linguistics - Sociolinguistic Program, 1974-1975
    - International Congress of Linguists, 1961-1962
    - International Linguistic Workshop, 1979-1982
    - International Pragmatics Conference, 1984-1985
    - International Reading Association, 1985-1986
    - International Research and Exchanges Board, 1983-1986
    - International Sociological Association - Research Committee on Sociolinguistics, 1965-1973,1979-1980
    - International Union of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences, 1964-1973,1976
    - Iowa State University Humanities Symposium - Myths and Minds: Games People Think, 1975
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1979,1981,1985
    - Joint Committee on Native American Languages / Conference on American Indian Languages, 1964-1967,1975
    - Lancaster-Lebanon Intermediate Unit - Oral Communication Seminar, 1979
    - Multilingual Multicultural Materials Development Center, 1976-1977
    - National Academy of Sciences - Committee on Scholarly Communication with the People's Republic of China, 1983
    - National Endowment for the Humanities - National Board of Consultants, 1981
    - National Foreign Language Resource Center, 1985-1986
    - National Institute of Mental Health
      - Ad Hoc Committee on the Behavioral Sciences, 1963-1967
      - Committee on Social and Cultural Processes, 1972-1973
      - Cultural Anthropology Fellowship Review Committee, 1970-1972
    - National Research Council - Committee on Basic Research in the Behavioral and Social Sciences, 1980,1984-1985
    - National Science Foundation - Advisory Panel for Anthropology, 1965-1971
    - Native American Orientation Institute (NAOI), 1973
    - New York State Teachers of English to Speakers of Other Languages and Bilingual Educators Association Conference, 1978
    - Northwestern University Renaissance Conference - Newberry Library, 1980-1981
    - Penn State University - Distinguished Guest Lecturer Series, 1981
    - Philadelphia Community College Faculty Seminars, 1985-1986
    - San Francisco State University - Sociolinguistics Conference - The Language We Bring to Teaching and Learning, 1977
    - Smithsonian Institution
      - Center for the Study of Man, 1968-1971
      - Native Americans Advisory Group (NAAG), 1972-1977; 2 folders
        - Folder 1, 1972-1974
        - Folder 2, 1975-1977
    - Socialist Scholars Conference, 1965-1967,1969
    - Society for Applied Anthropology, 1979,1981-1983
    - Southwestern University - The Brown Symposium, 1981-1983
    - Speech Communication Association, 1974-1975
    - Symposion der Werner Reimers-Stiftung - Philosophische Problemeder Anthropologie, 1970-1971
    - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO), 1963-1967, 1970-1973; 4 folders
      - Folder 1, 1963-1967
      - Folder 2, 1970
      - Folder 3, 1971
      - Folder 4, 1972-1973
    - United States-Australia Cooperative Science Program Seminar - Language in Cultural Context: The Frontier and Beyond, 1978-1982
    - University of Birmingham - Sociolinguistics Symposium, 1979-1981
    - University of California, Santa Cruz - Community Studies - External Review Team, 1981
    - University of Massachusetts, Amherst - Visiting Scholar Program, 1975
    - University of Massachusetts, Boston - Applied Linguistics Lecture Series, 1986
    - University of Pennsylvania
      - Annenberg School of Communication
        - Encyclopedia Feasibility Study, 1982-1984
        - Graduate Group in Communications, 1967-1970,1973,1975
      - Center for the Study of Art and Symbolic Behavior, 1978,1986
      - Christian Association, 1979-1987; 2 folders
        - Folder 1, 1979-1985
        - Folder 2, 1986-1987
      - Committee on Problems of War and Peace, 1966-1970
      - Graduate Program in Comparative Literature and Literary Theory, 1978-1979,1985
      - Interdisciplinary Committee for a Program in Language, Culture, and Society, 1979-1986; 2 folders
        - Folder 1, 1979-1981
        - Folder 2, 1982-1986
      - Language and Interaction Institute, 1974-1977
      - Language Attrition Project, 1978-1984; 3 folders
        - Folder 1, 1978-1979
        - Folder 2, 1980
        - Folder 3, 1981-1984
    - University of Pennsylvania Press - Haney Foundation Editorial Committee, 1967-1976; 2 folders
      - Folder 1, 1967-1971
      - Folder 2, 1972-1976
    - University of the State of New York - The State Education Department - Doctoral Evaluation Project, 1979-1981
    - University of Texas at Arlington - Conference on Linguistics and the Humanities, 1980-1981
    - University of Texas at Austin - Conference on the Ethnography of Speaking, 1970-1972
    - University of Washington - Walker-Ames Professor, 1983-1984
    - University of Wisconsin-Madison - Conference on Communicating in the Classroom, 1980
    - University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee - Symposium on Ethnopoetics, 1974-1975
    - Warm Springs Curriculum Project, 1973
    - Wenner-Gren Foundation for Anthropological Research
      - A Burg Wartenstein Symposium, 1964; 2 folders
      - Conference on Folklore and Social Science, 1967
      - Conference on the Nature and Function of Anthropological Traditions, 1965-1968, 1970-1971; 3 folders
        - Folder 1, 1965-1967
        - Folder 2, 1968
        - Folder 3, 1970-1971
          Including Notes
      - Correspondence, 1955-1975, 1980-1986; 3 folders
        - Folder 1, 1955-1967
        - Folder 2, 1968-1975
        - Folder 3, 1980-1986
      - Symposium on the Evolutionist Interpretation of Culture, 1964-1965
    - Werner Reimers Foundation - Colloquium History and Anthropology, 1975-1978
    - Workshop Exploring Qualitative/Quantitative Research Methodologies in Education, 1976-1977
    - Yale University - University Council Committee on Social Sciences - Behavioral, 1982-1984,1986
- Series III. Works by Hymes, 1947-1987; 3 lin. feet (Box 57-62)
  Hymes' typewritten and handwritten drafts, and outlines, preparatory notes, note cards, research for articles, books, reviews, lectures. Includes some of his editorial work as well. Arranged alphabetically by work title.
  - Works by Hymes, Hymes, Dell H.
    - American Council of Learned Societies. Fellowship application., 1952
    - American Journal of Sociology. Book Reviews., 1978,1979
    - American Structuralism. With John Fought. Bibliography, 1975
    - American Structuralism. With John Fought. Contents. Pages 1-94, 1975
    - American Structuralism. With John Fought. Corrections., 1975
    - American Structuralism. With John Fought. Footnotes., 1975
    - American Structuralism. With John Fought. Pages 95-166, 1975
    - American Structuralism. With John Fought. Pages 167-236, 1975
    - American Structuralism. With John Fought. Pages 237-339, 1975
    - American Structuralism. With John Fought. Pages 340-449, 1975
    - American Structuralism. With John Fought. Pages 450-571, 1975
    - Amsterdam Festival of Social Sciences. "Towards Linguistic Competence.", 1975
    - Anthropology & Education Quarterly. "Educational Ethnology", 1979-1983
    - Bibliography of Morris Swadesh, 1970
    - Bibliography of works., 1947-1985
    - Book Reviews., 1965-1969, 1972,1975,1978,1982-1983,1986, n.d.
    - Comments on Charles V. Hartung. "Toward a Science of Language.", 1962
    - Comments on I. M. Zeitlin. "The 'Plain' Marxism of C. Wright Mills", 1967
    - Comments on Y. A. Zamoshkin. "Scientific Analysis of Soviet Society", 1967
    - Communication. "Linguistics, Language, and Communication", 1972-1974
    - Conference on Individual Differences in Language Ability and Language Behavior. "Sapir, Competence, Voices", 1976,1979
    - "The Contributions to Linguistics of Edward Sapir.", [1983]
    - "Cross-Cultural Differences in the Role of Language", 1968
    - Current Trends in Linguistics XII "Anthropology and Sociology: an overview", 1971
    - Curriculum Vitae, n.d.
    - Daedalus. "Speech and Language: on the Origins and Foundations of Inequality among Speakers.", [1973]
    - Directions in Sociolinguistics. (with John Gumperz), 1971
    - The English Magazine. Article., 1980-1981
    - Explorations in the Ethnography of Speaking., 1973-1974
    - Forward to "Acquiring Conversational Competence" by Elinor Ochs and Bambi Schieffelin., 1982
    - Forward to "Language in the USA" by Charles A. Ferguson and Shirley Brice Heath (eds.), 1980